They have deceived the descendant of a hero,
to unknowingly dirty his own hands.
Taking Wang Lun's neck is a simple task.
Please wait a moment longer.
Chao Gai is
the Pagoda-Shifting Heavenly King.
Kill him.
4,000 soldiers
have been deployed from Beijing.
They aim for your neck, Chao Gai.
You will be killed.
It is a gamble I am willing to take.
I ask that you trust me, Song Jiang.
If I were Chao Gai,
there is only one place to escape to.
Clear a path for our future!
Halt.
Yes, sir?
Your sleeves.
Pardon?
They are stained.
My apologies, sir. I am but a clumsy man.
Is that so.
Li Fu.
A boat has made it across Liangshan Marsh.
Will Wang Lun allow Chao Gai to remain?
If he is denied entry,
we shall take his neck.
However, Wang Lun will lose his men's trust.
All will depend on Wang Lun's decision.
Does something bother you, sir?
His right sleeve was stained as well.
[Episode 6]
I am the Pagoda-Shifting Heavenly King.
I have come,
hearing this place is a haven
for those with qualms against this nation.
We must allow the Pagoda-Shifting
Heavenly King to enter, sir.
Hold your tongue.
I am rethinking my earlier decision.
If we allow him entrance,
we must fight the imperial army.
Sir, though they are an army of 4,000,
they have no ships to cross this marsh.
We cannot be fighting the nation's army.
Then you must make
the declaration yourself, sir.
Why? It is no obligation of mine
to confront those men.
Lin Chong, what are your thoughts?
You ought to know more about this army.
I was merely an instructor
for the Imperial Guard.
Do your loyalties lie elsewhere after all?
You suspect I am a dog of the Imperial Guard?
I gave you your chance to dispel my doubts,
yet you allowed Yang Zhi to live.
How distrustful must you be?
Then prove yourself to me, Lin Chong!
You are a pitiable man.
You do not trust a single soul.
You order your men to remain unarmed.
All while you stay protected
behind your two guards.
You dare disrespect me, Lin Chong?
I, Chao Gai of Yuncheng,
as well as six others,
have come to Liangshan
with 10,000 pieces of treasure
meant for a chancellor in Kaifeng.
Look here.
This is the sullied loot
that was to be delivered to Cai Jing.
He's captured the hearts of these hooligans
in an instant.
Now Wang Lun cannot chase us away so easily.
We have plundered the rich
in the name of honor,
and are now being chased
by the imperial army.
I request protection for the seven of us.
Will your leader Wang Lun uphold his honor,
and fight the imperial forces?
Or will he chase us away,
and take their side?
That is what I wish to know.
Who among you is Chao Gai?
You are speaking to him now.
Are those the bribes you have stolen?
Indeed.
We have not lain a finger
on these stolen treasures.
We instead hope to use them for the people.
And to that end, we hope you will aid us.
I respect your honorable soul, Chao Gai.
However, we of Liangshan
have our own rules to follow.
I alone cannot make the decision
to allow your stay.
I shall consult my men.
Await our verdict in the parlor.
We shall offer you liquor.
Thank you, but I shall decline.
My men and I will wait right here.
What a troublesome bunch indeed.
What shall we do?
We cannot make a hasty decision.
If any sympathize with Chao Gai and his men,
the imperial army will seize this place.
Do you fear the imperial army?
We must first strengthen our troops.
By continuing to attack innocents
and their cargo?
I have my ways.
Then will you kill these men?
You heard the support they garnered.
Kill them, and we will lose all power here.
Then what is our next move?
Tell them our fortress is full.
We cannot harbor any more men here.
You will chase them out with their treasures,
to evade conflict with the imperial army?
Yes.
Are you absolutely certain, sir?
My decision is final.
When we are ready,
I will wear a black obi.
That will be your cue.
Wang Lun.
You fear the imperial army.
You trample on the hearts of honorable men.
You even reject their treasures.
What does that make this stronghold?
Was this not a haven for like-minded souls?
A fortress, for those who share a heart?
You've shown your true colors, Lin Chong.
Kill him. Kill him!
Discard your weapons!
You have done well, Lin Chong.
It was my honor, sir.
Rumors are beginning to spread.
We must swiftly declare our victory,
and Wang Lun's death to the 3,000 others.
He was a pitiful man.
He once rallied the hearts of you men.
At a time, I do not doubt
he was a venerable leader.
Yet he unfortunately lost sight of his ways.
I will have to make a show
of Wang Lun's head.
But my intent is not to shame him.
Rather, it is to warn the rest of his fate.
Am I clear?
Yes, sir.
[Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name]
The rain and dark clouds have now passed.
We are all comrades,
enforcing the way in Heaven's name.
We are rogues.
We cannot abide by the rules
of those in Kaifeng.
We have the strength to fight.
We can save our people
who are oppressed by those in power.
This fortress shall be a perch
for those who save the weak.
For those who look to the same blue skies.
I now call this land, Mount Liang.
Mount Liang.
A wonderful name indeed.
He was no mere rabbit after all.
Indeed.
My presence is no longer of use.
I will return to the capital at once.
Remain here, and continue your observations.
Yes, sir.
Another salt road was extinguished?
Yes, sir. They are
becoming difficult to maintain.
Though we may excavate mountains
and procure our own supply,
if we have no modes of transport,
then they are merely sitting stock.
This is quite dire.
Those associated with the smuggling
are becoming known as well.
Then perhaps it is time
we exchange our managing parties.
Deng Li Hua.
Yes, Master Lu?
[Deng Li Hua, Lu Jun Yi's retainer]
I am sure you heard.
You will temporarily be removed
from overseeing our salt roads.
What shall I do in the meanwhile?
I have lost a path of communication
with Song Jiang.
I ask that you be our messenger
by acting as Song Jiang's mistress.
A mistress of Sir Song Jiang...
Do you find issue with this?
No, I am fine.
You have raised me like your own kin.
Any way I can repay you is an honor.
It vexes me that I cannot do a thing,
while Sir Chao Gai puts his life in danger.
Make no mistake. Our battle lies here.
Yan Qing.
This is our battlefield,
and money is my weapon.
We shall protect Chao Gai
with these weapons of ours.
A weapon...
We had two days of heavy rain.
I was worried you let yourself
be swept up by the stream.
But I see you are alive and well, Shi Jin.
Father.
You left before I could
give anything in return.
That itself, is another sin.
Young master!
The outlaws of Mount Shaohua!
They have finally sprung their attack!
Please, hurry!
Shi Jin, the Nine Tattooed Dragons.
I insist you allow us passage
through your family village.
Never.
You still choose to block our path?
Master Wang Jin...
I will be alive within you.
I know it to be true.
If you are set on hindering our way,
then I, Chen Da, the Stream-leaping Tiger,
shall take my iron spear
and pierce you where you stand.
[Chen Da, Mount Shaohua bandit]
Shi Jin, the Nine Tattooed Dragons.
I only wish to pass your village
to defeat corrupt officials.
Do you take their side?
I am only defending my village from bandits!
Who are the real bandits, Shi Jin?
Is it not the officials
who so boldly steal from their people?
Enough.
I'll silence you myself!
Shi Jin, the Nine Tattooed Dragons.
Did Wang Jin teach you
to take a life for such reasons?
Yes, you bested this man in combat.
But his words triumph over yours.
Who are you?
I am known as Lu Zhi Shen.
I am a friend of Wang Jin.
I came to deliver his letter,
only to come across this commotion.
Shi Jin, you are getting heated.
Calm yourself.
[Shi Jin]
[Venture out into the world.]
[Search for the meaning in your martial arts]
Shi Jin!
Shi Jin, the Nine Tattooed Dragons!
Again with the yelling?
Your home is quite rambunctious, Shi Jin.
Chen Da, you are alive!
Brothers...
State your names.
I am Zhu Wu.
[Zhu Wu, Chen Da's sworn brother]
This is Yang Chun.
[Yang Chun, Chen Da's sworn brother]
We are his sworn brothers.
I am glad our younger brother is well.
For if he were dead,
we would take our lives as well.
Why must you also die if he were dead?
The three of us are one whole,
who make up for the other's faults.
If even one of us perishes,
we will revert to mere bandits.
Please, do not kill our younger brother.
Three as one, is it?
What about Wang Jin enamored you?
Was it his strength alone?
Return to your brothers.
Chen Da!
I implore you to visit us at Mount Shaohua.
We'd like to share a drink with you.
Why his mistress?
What seems to be the matter?
I have committed a grave sin.
Not at all.
Deng Li Hua.
What I have done is unforgivable.
This was my choice alone.
Unforgivable as it may be.
You play dirty! Are you another foe?
The battlefield is unpredictable, sir.
You are easily put off balance.
You must strengthen your core.
Like so.
Again.
- Right.
- Go, Sir Song Jiang!
Brother.
Qing, what brings you here today?
[Song Qing, Song Jiang's younger brother]
What are you doing?
Oh, right. Qing, meet Zhu Tong, and Lei Heng.
The name is Zhu Tong, sir.
Though I was previously an Imperial Guard,
[Zhu Tong, Yuncheng Commander]
I now lead Yuncheng's equestrian unit.
Your elder brother requested we train him.
I am Lei Heng, sir.
[Lei Heng, Yuncheng Commander]
It is a pleasure to meet you, Sir Song Qing.
I have heard much from your brother.
This is Yan Po Xi.
A new woman.
Does your lust know no shame?
- You've brought in another woman!
- "Another"?
Qing, training would do good for you.
How about it?
Brother.
I, Song Qing,
have made love to Deng Li Hua.
Perhaps we'd best get going, Zhu Tong.
Yan Po Xi, come along.
Let us leave them.
Zhu Tong, hurry.
- Yan Po Xi!
- Sir Song Jiang!
- Come along now.
- Brother?
I see.
That is great news.
Great news?
Your own brother
has made love to your mistress!
Qing, I must head to my office.
Let us discuss this another time.
Brother, I have had enough.
You do not tell me a thing.
I only learn of things after the fact.
Brother!
I cannot get you involved, Qing.
Forgive me.
[Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name]
I am establishing a country.
We will begin the process
by organizing several chains of command.
- Wu Yong.
- Yes, sir.
Lin Chong.
Yes, sir.
You will command 300 equestrian soldiers
as part of Mount Liang's equestrian unit.
Train them well.
[Lin Chong]
Yes, sir.
Next, we will establish five infantry units,
comprised of 1,500 soldiers total.
Du Qian.
Song Wan.
Ruan Xiao Wu.
Jiao Ting.
Kong Ming. You five will lead these troops.
Gongsun Sheng.
[Gongsun Sheng]
You will expand your Zhisi Squad
from 50, to 300.
Gongsun Sheng will remain commander.
Shi Xiu, Kong Liang, Liu Tang,
and Yang Xiong will be your captains.
Yes, sir.
Those who wish to join the Zhisi Squadron
must truly understand what their job entails.
We will also establish a Civil Unit
to write, and enact our laws.
Xiao Rang, Jin Da Jian,
you will forge documents for us.
"Forge documents"?
Intel is oftentimes more crucial
than sheer manpower.
If we are able to forge commands,
we can confuse our enemies.
We must also establish a naval fleet.
Ruan Xiao Er. Ruan Xiao Qi.
You two will command our ships.
Mount Liang's strength
is in the marsh which surrounds it.
Your expertise as fishermen
will prove crucial to our defense.
An Dao Quan.
An Dao Quan?
He is in the clinic,
making medicines with Xue Yong.
An Dao Quan and Xue Yong will run our clinic.
Bai Sheng.
You will be the bridge between us
and those medicine-obsessed doctors.
Yes, sir.
Chai Jin will provide the logistics
of transporting our men and supplies.
Zhu Gui will continue to hide our boats.
I ask that he teaches our chefs
a thing or two as well.
The food here tastes terrible at best.
Leave it to me, sir.
To our smithies.
The population of Mount Liang will only grow.
We will need farms and farmhouses for crops.
[Chao Gai]
[Mount Liang]
[Blacksmith]
[Clinic]
[Examination Room]
Here you go.
Drink.
[Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name]
[Assembly Hall]
[Song Jiang]
Song Jiang.
Come join me soon.
Thank you.
Sir... Song Jiang?
Flowers...
Sir Song Jiang...
[Shi Xiu, Zhisi Squadron Captain]
Are these our potential recruits?
Lin Chong.
Gongsun Sheng.
I have brought you men
worthy of the Zhisi Squadron.
The Zhisi Squadron.
A squad faced with certain death.
We do not desire fame, nor fortune.
Our job sees no merit, nor promotions.
We do not even leave a name behind.
We do not think of living another day.
We simply share a dream, and fight.
Those who die, perish as unknowns.
They will not live on in the people's hearts.
However, I alone will not forget.
We will not forget.
Zhisi Squadron's men will live on
in each other's hearts.
Those who take pride in such an end...
Step forward,
towards your imminent death.
Your first task.
Scale this cliffside.
Yes, sir.
Defect, like I have.
Leave, and you will find your path!
Do you still defend
this utterly corrupt nation?
Enough.
That mark on your face.
You must be Yang Zhi, the Blue-faced Beast.
Who are you?
Have you forgotten?
We once met at Lu Jun Yi's abode.
You speak the truth?
Indeed. We had been searching for him.
Thankfully, the Splitting Hairs Blade
stands out.
How is he?
Yang Zhi has lost his home, and his riches.
If Yan Qing had not found him,
who knows what he would have done.
We've wounded his self-esteem.
If we had not ensnared him,
his overall worth was doomed to plummet.
You speak like a true merchant.
If we left him be,
even a mere official could capture him.
An official like myself, perhaps?
Pardon me.
We meet again, Yang Zhi,
the Blue-faced Beast.
And you are?
I am but a humble clerk.
But my name, is Song Jiang.
Song Jiang...
I have never seen an official
assist a peddler.
What is your name?
My name is Song Jiang.
I am a local clerk.
So you have come to capture me.
No.
I could never stand against
a strong man like yourself.
Your Splitting Hairs Blade
would easily slice me in half.
Then why have you come?
There is something I would like to show you.
Yang Zhi, would you join me
on an outing tomorrow?
What is all this?
The aftermath of a bandit attack?
Yes.
Is there anyone alive?
Anyone at all?
They are all dead.
Anyone?
The Yuncheng Office
was notified of the attack three days ago.
I only found out last night.
The whole incident had been silenced.
Why?
Why do officials ignore these people in need?
Because they receive no orders to send aid.
No orders?
Compared to us officials,
bandits here triumph
in both numbers and strength.
Take action, and incur the wrath
of the wrong bandit,
and an official is sure
to lose any chance at a promotion.
Then they are no better
than the bandits themselves!
They sit in their homes,
enjoying their meals,
all while the poor must suffer.
How can they do such a thing?
Soldiers only need to follow orders.
What?
I suspect that was your life's motto.
And officials are the same.
They obey their orders.
How can you act so calm at a time like this?
Do I look calm to you?
What is it I should do?
You were a man raised as a soldier,
yet now you are without orders.
You do not know what to do next.
I suspect I am right?
Do you have the answer to my conundrum?
Can you not hear these cries?
Though silent, the people are crying out.
Their pleas ought to be your orders.
The pleas of our people...
We call this, the mandate of Heaven.
Yang Zhi, the Blue-faced Beast.
My apologies, Yuan Ming.
Close call, I say.
Drop the ball you kick, and you are no more.
Tang Niu Er.
Yes, sir.
A secret organization spearheaded
by Chancellor Cai Jing, you say?
Yes, sir.
[Shi Qian, Song Jiang's spy]
They apprehended Lin Chong,
raised the price of salt,
and ultimately deployed soldiers
to corner Chao Gai.
Only a few in Kaifeng
know of this organization.
And you said their name was...
The Qinglian Temple.
Qinglian Temple.
Given they know Chao Gai
is the Pagoda-Shifting Heavenly King,
our identities may be compromised as well.
Halt.
Your sleeves, they are stained.
That man's glare.
It sent quite the shiver down my spine.
That indescribable gaze.
Li Fu saw my face.
Shi Qian, I must ask you a request.
What is it, sir?
Please deliver this letter to Ma Gui,
and have her leave this line of work.
If she continues as a spy,
her life will certainly be in danger.
You care much for a mere spy like her.
My words do not convince Ma Gui.
I hope you can convince her,
from one spy to another.
Yes, sir.
Tang Niu Er.
Miss Yan Po Xi!
Why are you loitering about? It's hot today.
They've chased me out.
Secret talks and all.
But look at your sweat...
I am a servant. I am used to this treatment.
If only they would let us in
on their secrets.
You still do not know her master?
Her name was Ma Gui, was it?
Yes, sir. Though we have tailed her,
she acts as both spy,
and traveling entertainer.
Then why is her master yet a mystery?
She visits a plethora of locals and places.
We cannot trace who exactly she serves.
Perhaps she has noticed your presence,
and is leading you astray?
I do not believe so.
Allow her to roam a while longer.
A third-rate spy
will leave a trail in due time.
Ma Gui.
Shi Qian.
You failed to notice my presence.
Why have you tailed me?
I have a message from Sir Song Jiang.
I will write a reply.
He said that will not be necessary.
Then I shall go to him directly.
Calm yourself.
I have served him with my life. So why...
You failed to notice my presence
till I called out.
You are unable to suppress your emotions,
and speak loudly of our secrets.
Can you truly call yourself a spy
worthy of protecting Song Jiang's vision?
If you will put Song Jiang in danger,
then I must silence you.
Do not make me take such an extreme.
I am excused from the Imperial Guard?
Why?
Allow me to see the Emperor!
- There has to be some mistake!
- Please go back.
Why?
Emperor, sir!
Again!
Heave-ho!
Put your backs into it!
This flag depicts our ambitions.
It is only obvious it would be heavy!
Chao Gai, we shall handle this!
Heave-ho!
Pull!
[Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name]
Doctor! Doctor!
Look!
Do not rest.
Again.
[Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name]
Go on, speak.
Chao Gai has become the new leader.
The fortress is now called "Mount Liang".
Mount Liang.
A place for those evil-doers to remain.
Or something of the sort.
Then they have established their perch.
Now to see how it will grow.
All their pieces will gather there.
Damn it all...
Your sleeves, they are stained.
My apologies, sir. I am but a clumsy man.
Our fight is not over.
Pardon?
"Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name".
The author for this script remains at large.
You mean it is not Chao Gai?
How can that be?
Chao Gai is a cunning, pragmatic man.
Yet this author has a child's heart.
He undoubtedly believes
in his idealistic dreams.
It seems you have an idea who this author is.
Mother?
Po Xi...
Make a report to Wang He.
Ma Gui has a daughter.
Her name is Po Xi.
You fool!
The leader cannot go
and put himself in danger.
That is how I establish a country.
No emperor would do such a thing!
Which is why these countries fall to ruin!
You will abandon a mere child?
Brother, you are more than a mere clerk.
I am certain you are hiding something.
I entrust my back to you, Yang Zhi.
Mount Erlong.
Lead a group of bandits, you say?
Will you become a bandit yourself?
We do away with rotten officials,
and extinguish all embers of a revolution.
Would you please become this child's mother?
You have a daughter, named Yan Po Xi.
We will bring her misery.
Song Jiang!
The fault is mine alone to bear.
[Episode 6 - FIN]